# **Ifrah Mohamed**

(206) 240-3203 | <a href="mailto:linkedin.com/in/ifrahm22">lifrahm.github.io</a> | Seattle, WA

#### **EDUCATION**

## **University of Washington**

Sept 2018 – Anticipated June 2022

• B.S in Informatics (Human-Computer Interaction), Information School, GPA: 3.5

## SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS

Programming: JavaScript • Node.js • Java • Python • R • PHP/MySQL • SQL • HTML • CSS

Design: Interaction Design • Use Cases • Wireframes • Rapid Prototyping • User Personas

Research: Affinity Diagrams • Customer Experience and Journey Maps • Contextual Inquiry • Survey & Interviews

Tools: Figma • Marvel • Photoshop • Power BI

Courses: Computer Programming I & II • Web Development • Statistical Computing • Mobile Design • Data Science

## **EXPERIENCE**

# ServiceNow, Program Management Intern

June 2021 - Sept 2021

- Revitalized Mobile release Calendar resulting in increased functionality, effectiveness, and usability
- Caried out communication plan to prepare stakeholders for change

## UCSD Design Lab, HCI Research Intern

June 2021 - Sept 2021

- Designed high-fidelity news article featuring enhancements to increase users engagements with data visualizations
- Built out features onto a react application

Microsoft. Al Intern

June 2018 - Aug 2018

- Transformed large data sets into visualizations with Power Bi to display traffic flow in intersections from live streams
- Collaborated with fellow teammates to create an innovative program featuring image video analytics that reads traffic lights in partnership with the city of Bellevue. Presented project content at two showcases at end of internship

#### **PROJECTS**

## Trackity — Front-End Developer

June 2021

- Front-end developer on a job application tracker web app targeted towards undergrads
- Implemented login functionality utilizing firebase, increased interactivity, applied good practice UX writing resulting in an improved user experience

#### **Life in Lockdown** — Front-End Developer

Nov 2020

• Front-end developer on a 24hr hackathon collaboration project that gives a holistic view of the problems people face in quarantine using Unreal Engine 4.

#### What's That Word — Full Stack Developer

Feb 2020

• Created a website that allows the user to enter a word in a text box and choose a category utilizing the fetch API to asynchronously request and process response data on the site using JavaScript.

## A Helping Hand — UX Designer/Research

Mar 2019

- Lead UX designer in creating a high-fidelity social platform using Figma to help seniors and their caretakers with daily activities.
- Drove ideation from general platform to being more user tailored through extensive user research on seniors housing decision making

# **LEADERSHIP**

#### National Society of Black Engineers, Region VI Finance Chair

May 2020 - May 2021

- Surpassed target corporate revenue by 80% for the Region VI Fall Regional Conference
- Refined corporate contact spreadsheet to maximize performance

# National Society of Black Engineers, Programs Chair (UW Chapter)

Sept 2019 - June 2020

- Provided resources and mission-driven guidance to the members to excel academically and professionally
- Planned various events that required budgeting for location, problem solving, and securing keynote speakers.

#### Somali Student Association, Internal Development (UW Chapter)

Sept 2019 - Jul 2020

- Led general meetings to foster friendship and communication amongst SSA members and promote upcoming events.
- Brainstormed and implemented high quality meeting plans to increase engagement and communication.